Robert Hare Papers 1764-1859 Mss.B.H22
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence
  - J. B. Smyth to Robert Hare, 1856 Dec. 15 (Box 3)
    Rockford, Illinois; A.L.S. 3p. Concerning chemical action on corn by adding water, with ammonia as a result.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1856 Dec. 31; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning his communication on the manufacture of weights and measures. Concerning De Bendt and the Smithsonian.
  - Smithsonian Institution to Robert Hare, 1857 Jan. 1; Smithsonian Institution. (Box 3)
    Washington, L.S.: Joseph Henry, Sec. 1p. and end. Informs him of date of meeting of the Board of Regents.
  - Charles Partridge to Robert Hare, 1857 Jan. 17 (Box 3)
    New York, L.S. 4p. Concerning his publications by Partridge and Britton.
  - S. B. Britton to Robert Hare, 1857 Jan. 30 (Box 3)
    New York, L.S. 1p. Partridge & Britton will try to publish his paper shortly. Suggests an article on spiritualism and science.
  - Robert Hare to the President of the Agricultural Society of the U.S. Philadelphia Society for Promoting Agriculture (?), 1857 Jan.; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    A.D. 3p. and end. Draft. Concerning the manufacture of an artificial guano.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1857 Feb. 3; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning Espy, Redfield, and his [Hare's] theories of tornadoes. Concerning Maury and his work on the seas.
  - Charles Partridge to Robert Hare, 1857 March 17 (Box 3)
    New York, A.L.S. 4p. Publications and attempts to settle accounts between Hare and Partridge & Britton.
  - Charles Partridge to Robert Hare, 1857 March 30 (Box 3)
    New York, A.L.S. 4p. Business differences over publications.
  - Alexander D. Bache to Joseph Henry, 1857 April 3; Bache, A.D., (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867 (Box 3)
    Savannah, Georgia, L. 1p. Copy. Concerning Hare's instrument for weights and measures. Enclosed originally in letter from Smithsonian institution to Hare; April 7, 1857.
  - Smithsonian Institution to Robert Hare, 1857 April 7; Smithsonian Institution. (Box 3)
    L.S.: Joseph Henry, Sec. 1p. Enc. Encloses letter of A.D.Bache pertaining to his instrument for weights and measures For enclosure, see: A.D.Bache to J. Henry; April 3, 1857.
  - B. P. Newman to Robert Hare, 1857 May 7 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Asks for help for engravers to make clearer lines in their work.
  - Concerning Christianity, 1857 May 8 (Box 3)
  - H. F. Gardner to Robert Hare, 1857 June 8 (Box 3)
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning the forwarding of his publications in England. Is involved in an argument with Agassiz, etc. on spiritualism and medicine.
  - Robert Hare to Benjamin Silliman, 1857 June 8; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p. Draft. Spiritualism.
  - Robert Hare to Partridge and Brittan, 1857 June 12; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, L.S. 4p. Concerning books sent as gifts to friends in England.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1857 July 7; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    L.S. 1p. Concerning his article on tornadoes.
  - H. F. Gardner to Robert Hare, 1857 July 23 (Box 3)
    Boston, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning the investigation of spiritualism by Agassiz, etc.
  - S. W. Rodman to Robert Hare, 1857 Sept. 10 (Box 3)
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Encloses check for dividends.
  - Francis Peters to Robert Hare, 1857 Sept. 28 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 5p. Asks questions concerning water density.
  - Charles Partridge to Robert Hare, 1857 Sept. 28 (Box 3)
    New York, L. 1p. Concerning his publication in stock.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, 1857 Oct. 15; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 2p. Credit system of the country and his pamphlet on it. Friendly letter.
  - William B. Aitkin to Robert Hare, 1857 Oct. 19 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. Concerning shipment of "spiritscope" to Texas.
  - Charles Partridge to Robert Hare, 1857 Nov. 28 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 1p. Forwarding publication.
  - Charles Partridge to Robert Hare, 1857 Dec. 31 (Box 3)
    New York, L. 2p. Concerning the publication of his writings.
  - Charles Partridge to Robert Hare, 1857? (Box 3)
    L.S. 9p. Incomplete. Concerning his publications. Concerning his work on spiritualism.
  - Robert Hare to James Ruggles, 1858 Feb. 17 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 3p. and end. Draft. Wishes to supervise his son's studies of medicine.
  - James Ruggles to Robert Hare, 1858 Feb. 18 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Needs financial aid to train his son in medicine.
  - Robert Hare to James Ruggles, 1858 Feb. 19 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 2p. and end. Draft. Concerning the medical education of his son.
  - J. L. Gatchet to Robert Hare, 1858 Feb. 27 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerning lightning rods.
  - John F. Gray and E. H. Gray to Robert Hare, 1858 March 10. (Box 3)
    A.L.S.: John F. Gray and P. S. by Mrs. E. H. Gray. 2p. Has made inquiries to Mr. Partridge as requested.
  - Charles Partridge to Robert Hare, 1858 April 20 (Box 3)
    New York, L. 1p. Has forwarded copies of his new edition.
  - S. A. Peters. Statement concerning Dr. Hare's experiments with spiritualism, 1858 April 20 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, D.S. 2p., end.
  - R. H. Hare to ---, 1858 May 8 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 3p. Medical treatment through spiritualism.
  - Robert Hare to James Ruggles, 1858 May 8; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, L. 4p. Concerning his son's interest in the study of medicine.
  - M. Gieb to Robert Hare, 1858 May 10 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Does not visit him for fear of upsetting him. Hopes he gets well soon.
  - William Pepper and Joseph Pancoast. Statement..., 1858 May 11; Pepper, William, 1810-1864 (Box 3)
    A.L.S.: William Pepper and Joseph Pancoast. 1p. and end.
  - Robley Dunglison to Robert Hare, 1858 May 14; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 2p. Will join his doctor, Pancoast, to wait on him, if his gout permits.
  - University of Pennsylvania Medical Faculty. Resolution upon the death of Robert Hare, 1858 May 18; University of Pennsylvania. Medical School--Faculty (Box 3)
    A.D.S.: R. E. Rogers. 2p.
  - Robley Dunglison to Harriet Clark Hare, 1858 Oct. 1 (Box 3)
    Philadelphia, Oct. 1, 1858. A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards minute of Jefferson Medical College referring to the death of Robert Hare.
  - Fitzgerald to Dr. Hare, 1858 (Box 3)
    A.L.S. 1p. Bill for publications and will give him one column a week.
  - Robert Hare to Benjamin Silliman, Jan. 17
    Refers to publications and apparatus. Mentions Mr. Bishop.
  - Joseph Henry to Robert Hare, Jan. 19; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878 (Box 4)
    A.L.S. 3p. He must bill the Smithsonian for cost of ozone apparatus.
  - Hare to Robert Hare?, Jan. 31 (Box 4)
    L. 4p. Incomplete. Is too ill to travel and cannot go to London.
  - Robert Hare to Robert Walsh, Feb. 20; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.L.S. 4p., end. Regarding articles in the National Gazette concerning the University.
  - Robert Hare to ---, March 30 (Box 4)
    Philadelphia, A.L. 2p. Fragment. Wonders at his objection for a man "doing me this Kindness".
  - William H. Roper to Robert Hare, March 30 (Box 4)
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Mutilated. Legacy of Mrs. Hare.
  - Mr. and Mrs. Wildes to Robert Hare, May (Box 4)
    L. in 3rd. p. 1p. Invitation to dinner.
  - Robert Hare to Alfred Elwyn, June 9 (Box 4)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p., end. Draft. Concerning converting dead dogs into fertilizer.
  - Thomas S. Kirkbride to Robert Hare, July 9; Kirkbride, Thomas Story, 1809-1883 (Box 4)
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Thanks for lathe. Concerning need for chemical apparatus, etc.. See 1840 July 20
  - Robert Hare to Benjamin Silliman, July 26
    Refers to publications, including engravings.
  - Robert Hare to Joseph Curwen, Oct. 20; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. and end. Invites him to dinner.
  - [Hare] to Robert Hare, undated (Box 4)
    Sunday
  - Fanny Butler to Robert Hare, undated (Box 4)
    Monday. A.L.S. 1p. Hopes to entertain him.
  - [Hare] to Robert Hare, undated (Box 4)
    Monday
  - M. Wellesley to Robert Hare, undated (Box 4)
    Monday. A.L.S. 2p. Will see him at 4:00 tomorrow.
  - I. J. Chapman to Robert Hare, undated (Box 4)
    Tuesday. A.L.S. 1p. Forwards invitation for him to visit the Athenaeum club.
  - M. A. Wellesley to Robert Hare, undated (Box 4)
    Tuesday. A.L.S. 2p. Cannot see him tomorrow.
  - R. T. Willing to Robert Hare, undated (Box 4)
    Tuesday. A.L.S. 11p. Concerning their discussion on spiritualism.
  - Hare to Robert Hare, undated (Box 4)
    Thursday. L. 12p. Hopes they can get together before winter. Friendly letter.
  - Hare to Robert Hare, undated (Box 4)
    Thursday. L. 8p. Family news. Friendly letter.
  - Amelia Lloyd to "Dear Delia", undated (Box 4)
    Friday. A.L.S. 4p. Enoyed the "joyous occasion." Plans for the summer. Friendly letter.
  - Mary W. McTavish to Robert Hare, undated (Box 4)
    Saturday. A.L.S. 2p. Her aunt is ill, that is why she writes for her.
  - A.J. Brady to Robert Hare, undated (Box 4)
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the publication of his article on spiritualism.
  - John Cusolle to Robert Hare, undated (Box 4)
    New York. A.L.S. 1p. and end. Asks chemical formula for cognac oil. Spiritualism.
  - Elisha De Butts and Robert Hare. Agreement..., undated (Box 4)
  - Extracts from magazines..., undated (Box 4)
  - A. Hare to Harriet Clark Hare, undated (Box 4)
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Will dine with her on Thursday.
  - M. Hare to Robert Hare, undated (Box 4)
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning the Hare genealogy.
  - Article to the editors of the Franklin Journal, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858; Robert Hare (Box 4)
    L. 4p. Concerning specific heat of elastic fluids. Refers to the APS.
  - Bills..., undated; Robert Hare (Box 4)
    D. 7 items. Various sizes.
  - Chemist's apology, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    D. 4p. and end.
  - Concerning electricity, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    D. 1p. and end. "This theory has had the sanction of my spirit friends, the famous Franklin..."
  - Concerning gold, credit, etc., undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    D. 10p.
  - Concerning his difference in views with Peltier..., undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    D. 9p. and end. Concerning his difference in views with Peltier respecting tornadoes.
  - Concerning his gift of apparatus to the Smithsonian, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
  - Concerning paper money, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
  - Concerning religion, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    D. 2p. and end.
  - Concerning the gas ram, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    D. 6p. and end. Various sizes.
  - Concerning the Irish and the British, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    D. 1p. and end. Draft.
  - Concerning the mails and the railroads, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.D.S. 1p. and end.
  - Concerning the manufacture of fish guano, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.D. 2p. (Read to the APS?)
  - Concerning the meaning of "Yankee annexation", undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.D. 4p.
  - Concerning the slaughtering houses, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.D. 1p. and end. States how offensive odors may be kept down.
  - Concerning tornadoes, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
  - Cost of apparatus incurred in making experiments..., undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.D. 1p. Draft. "...agreeably to an understanding with Professor Henry".
  - Despretendus Principes de Liebig, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.D. 4p. Partly in French, and partly in another hand.
  - Endorsement sheets, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    D. 17 items. Various sizes. Miscellany.
  - Errors of our Whig politicians, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    D. 8p. and end.
  - Gift of apparatus to the Smithsonian Institution, undated; Robert Hare (Box 4)
    A.D. 2p. and end. Draft.
  - Instructions for pressing gun-cotton, undated; Robert Hare (Box 4)
    A.D. 3p. and end. Draft.
  - Letter to Lord Ashburton, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.L. 1p. Incomplete. Sorry to have missed seeing him.
  - Letter to Count Cancrin, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.L. 2p. and add. Draft. Concerning his experiments on iridium and platinum. Count Cancrine [George, i.e., Igor Frankovitch Cancrin].
  - Letter to Count Cancrin, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    L. 3p. and end. In French. Concerning his experiments on iridium and platinum. ---Copy. 3p. and end. 10x8. "Le Comte Cancrine" [George, i.e., Igor Frankovitch Cancrin]. In French.
  - Letter to Count Cancrin, undated; Robert Hare (Box 4)
    A.L. 3p. and end. Draft. In French. Concerning iridium and mining. "Le Comte Cancrine" [George, i.e., Igor Frankovitch Cancrin].
  - Letter to Carey and Lea, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.L. 2p. Draft. States that they have plates for one of his publications, and he wants them.
  - Letter to the editors of the Chemist, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.L. 2p. and end. Draft. Concerning his chemical nomenclature. Refers to the APS.
  - Letter to the editors..., undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    L. 1p. and end. Praises Federalism and Federalists.
  - Letter to the editor of the Enquirer and National Gazette, undated; Robert Hare (Box 4)
    A.L.S. 3p. and end. Draft. Lightning rods and their use.
  - Letter to the editors of the North American and the U.S. Gazette, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.L.S. 2p. Draft. Did not attack the goverment in his speech before the AAAS.
  - Letter to Joseph Henry, undated; Robert Hare (Box 4)
    A.L. 1p. Incomplete. Draft. Concerning De Bendt and his apparatus.
  - Letter to Oliver Kane, undated; Robert Hare (Box 4)
  - Letter to the National Intelligencer, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    L. 2p.and end. Concerning imponderable matter.
  - Letter to Charles Partridge, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.L. 4p. Draft. Concerning publications and expenses.
  - Letter to Partridge and Brittan, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.L. 4p. Draft. Concerning expenses of publication.
  - Letter to the University of Pennsylvania Committee of the Trustees..., undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 4)
    A.L. 2p. and end. Draft. To the Trustees appointed to confer with the Medical Faculty. Concerning instruction and teaching in the medical school.
  - Letter to William Wagner, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 5)
    A.L.S. 1p. and end. Copy. Will lend apparatus to the Wagner Institute. Will give electrical apparatus.
  - Letter to the Revd. Dr. Wilson, Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 5)
    A.L.S. 3p. Draft. Incomplete. Disputes uses of words. Concerning light.
  - Letter to ----, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 5)
    A.L. 2p. Draft. Incomplete. Concerning storms and electrical discharges.
  - Letter to ----, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 5)
    A.L.S. 2p. Draft. Concerning cycloidal curves and tornadoes.
  - A List of Fixed Stars..., undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 5)
    D. 1p. Concerning light distance.
  - List of glass and porcelain apparatus, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858; Robert Hare (Box 5)
    D. 8p.
  - Memorandum on Voltaire at Ferney, Robert Hare (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous notes on political matters, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 5)
    D. 10. Various sizes. Attacks Whigs and Locofocos.
  - Miscellaneous notes on slavery, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 5)
    A.D. 7p. Various sizes. Anti-slavery sentiments.
  - Miscellaneous notes on storms, undated; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858 (Box 5)
    A.D. 8p. Various sizes.
  - Notes on chemistry, undated; Robert Hare (Box 5)
    A.D. 3p.
  - Observations on Guyot on clairvoyance, undated; Robert Hare (Box 5)
    A.D. 2p.and end. Draft.
  - On lecturing students, undated; Robert Hare (Box 5)
    A.D. 2p. Draft. Incomplete.
  - On poverty, undated; Robert Hare (Box 5)
    A.D. 5p.
  - On the patronage given chemistry by governments, Robert Hare (Box 5)
  - Poetry, undated; Robert Hare (Box 5)
    D. 29 leaves. Various sizes.
  - Process of electrolysis, undated; Robert Hare (Box 5)
    A.D. 1p. and end.
  - Scraps and miscellany, undated; Robert Hare (Box 5)
    A.D. 12 leaves. Various sizes. Letters and notes, including item dated 1791. One item in French.
  - Travelling on the Great Lakes, undated; Robert Hare (Box 5)
  - List of chemicals in Dr. Hare's cabinet, undated (Box 5)
  - List of communications by Dr. Hare, undated (Box 5)
  - Arthur McClelland to Robert Hare, undated (Box 5)
    A.L.S. 4p., end. Thanks for publications.
  - Mary W. Mactavish to Robert Hare, undated (Box 5)
  - Mary W. Mactavish to Robert Hare, undated
    A.L.S. 2p. Aunt Wellesley cannot see him tomorrow, due to ill health.
  - E. P. to "Mary", undated (Box 5)
    L.S. with initials. 7p. Concerning nature, religion, death of brother.
  - Charles Partridge to Dr. Hare, undated (Box 5)
  - Partridge and Brittan to Robert Hare, undated (Box 5)
    L. 2p. Business.
  - Partridge and Brittan to Robert Hare, undated (Box 5)
    L. 2p. Fragment. Concerning publications for him.
  - Solutions to mathematical problems, undated; George M. Ransom (Box 5)
    to Robert Hare. D.S. 15 items. Various sizes.
  - M. Salter. Receipt of Mrs. Murray, undated (Box 5)
    D. 1p. For £3.50.
  - Fr. Serturner to Robert Hare, undated (Box 5)
    A.L.S. 4p., end. In German. Friendly, general letter.
  - Mrs. Thomas to Mrs. McDonald, undated (Box 5)
    A.L.S. 1p. and end. Introduces Dr. Hare.
  - Extracts from Magazines, undated
    For taking out ink spots from linen, and for making mortar for roofs.
  - No.1 Robert Hare. Lectures on chemistry, undated
  - No.2. George Washington, Martha Washington, George Wythe, Major André, and Arnold Benedict facsimiles (Box 5)
    Facsimiles. 24 items. Various sizes.
  - No.3. Robert Hare. Account book of Robert and Harriet Clark Hare, 1806-1829 (Box 5)
    D. 1 vol. consisting of 96 leaves.
  - No.4. Robert Hare. On the suppositious travelling whirlwinds called Cyclones, undated (Box 5)
    D. 55p. and engravings. Copy, bound in volume.
- Series II. Robert Hare Scrolls
  Originally consisting of sheets of paper affixed end to end and rolled into cylinders, the scrolls appear primarily to be rough drafts of manuscripts or notes for works intended for publication.
  The scrolls are an important resource for study of the intellectual conformation of Hare's world. In them, he touches on the full range of his interests, from chemistry and electricity to meteorology, opposition to the Mexican War, viticulture, national politics, social and political duties, slavery, Spiritualism and religion, tariffs, banking, and finance.
  A relentless anti-Democrat as much as a Federalist, Hare is a brusk, no-holds-barred writer who seldom shied from controversy in politics, religion, morality or science.
  - Additional remarks on the speculations of Faraday and Exley, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Address to the Society for the Advancement of Agriculture, Robert Hare (Box 7)
    Includes draft and copy.
    Originally in a scroll; flattened: Oct. 1974. Filed with Series I: Correspondence.
  - America's duty to the Negro, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Analogy between the mode of existence of latent heat and other, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Apparatus for the evolution of oxygen, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Article on the War of 1812, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Autobiographical sketch, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Change in the relative prices of gold and silver, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Chemistry lectures, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - The claims of Texas, and the claims of the United States, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Classification of the voters in a republic with universal suffrage agreeably to experience, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Communication by a Filmorite. For the Inquirer, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - A Communication supplementary to that republished in the National Intelligencer on the 16th of September last respecting Espy's report on storms, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning charity; a lecture to medical students, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning cycloidal storms, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning electricity, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning electricity and spiritualism, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning explosiveness of hydrogen, etc., Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning heated air and storms, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning lightning and storms, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning rotary storms tornadoes, cyclones, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning Seneda, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning storms, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning storms and variable winds, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning the causes for storms, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning the consumption of food and the chemical reactions in the body to it, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning the Cycloidograph, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning the Democratic Party, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning the Democrats and slavery, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning the elements in vegetables and bodies, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning the Exhibition, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning the horrors of great storms, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning the making of meteorological observations all over the U.S. theory of storm, proposed by Guyot, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning the pledges given by General Taylor, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning the raising of grapes around Philadelphia, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning the Smithsonian Institution, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning the theory of storms, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning the University of Pennsylvania, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning thunder clouds and electricity, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning tornadoes and storms, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning tornadoes, or water-spouts, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning U.S. national politics, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Concerning William Charles Redfield's theory of rotary storms, Robert Hare (Box 7)
  - Cycloidal curves, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Cycloidal curves, Instrument for creating Cycloidograph, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Cycloidal storms, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - A defence of the banking system, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Demonstration that a disk of air cannot undergo a rotary motion without dividing its motion with the surrounding continguous non-moving portions of the fluid, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Description of apparatus for the Smithsonian?, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - An effort to reconcile the received doctrine respecting the existence of caloric with the undulatory theory respecting light, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Electrical plate machine of a convenient size to be used upon a table, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Explanation of a cycloidograph, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - Faraday's speculation touching electric conduction, and the nature of matter, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - For the Inquirer. "Mr. Breckenridge exults in the superior endurance and consequent powers of Democracy so called, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - For the Inquirer. On the American democracy, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - For the Merchants Magazine. Suggestions arising from a perusal of the report of the Committee on Finance of the Senate, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - For the National Intelligencer, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - For the National Intelligencer. On European writers in accounting for the success of republican government in the United States, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - For the National Intelligencer. On mail, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - For the National Intelligencer. On railroads carrying mail, Robert Hare (Box 8)
  - For the National Intelligencer. On the International copyright, Robert Hare (Box 8)